MUTHUKAMATCHI MANICKAM

QA AUTOMATION ENGINEER (Belgium Long Stay D Visa)

kamu@belyf.com | +32-494-80-87-16 | https://linkedin.com/in/kamu-m



SUMMARY

An insightful, passion-driven IT professional with around 7 years of extensive experience in the software testing lifecycle, including designing, developing, and implementing comprehensive automated test plans, test suites, and test processes. Proven track record in identifying critical bugs, achieving user acceptance, and enhancing software reliability.

ACHIEVEMENTS

- Reduced testing time by 50% using advanced automated testing methodologies.
- Mentored and trained over 5 junior engineers, improving team skills and efficiency.
- Followed bug tracking processes, resolving critical bugs thereby enhancing software reliability.
- Improved application performance by 30% through comprehensive performance testing.
- Enhanced test coverage by 25% using AI tools such as TestSigma.

AREA OF EXPERTISE

Automation Testing, CI/CD Implementation, Performance Testing, Load Testing, Database Testing, API Testing, Agile Methodologies, Version Control (Git), Test Framework Development, Mentorship & Training, Cross-Functional Collaboration, Process Improvement, Software Quality Assurance, Test Plan Development

TECHNICAL EXPERTISE

Robotframework, Python, Java, Selenium, TestSigma, TestNG, Locust, Jenkins, MongoDB, Elasticsearch, Git, JIRA, Confluence, UFT, VB Script, Chai, Mocha, Gherkin/Cucumber, HP ALM, SoapUI, TestRail

WORK EXPERIENCE

Aspire Systems.

Chennai, India Jan 2022 – Present

Test Lead

Client: Lendkey (https://www.lendkey.com/)

- Technologies include Robotframework, Python, TestSigma, Locust, Git.
- Developed robot scripts from scratch for two projects (Verify and Ocrolus) and set up Jenkins CI/CD pipelines.
- Contributed significantly to critical projects, earning client appreciation.
- Implemented load testing scripts in Locust for the Verify project.
- Conducted a successful PoC in Testsigma and applied it to the Aliro project.

Cognizant Technology Solutions.

Chennai, India

Associate

Jun 2018 – Jan 2022

Client: Opsec Security Group (https://www.opsecsecurity.com/)

- Technologies include Java, Selenium, TestNG, Mongo, Git
- Automated test cases and developed Keyword and Data-driven frameworks using Selenium WebDriver and TestNG.
- Wrote Mongo and Elastic Queries for testing and used Git for version control.
- Tested REST APIs and web applications, maintaining stories, test plans, and execution
 cycles in JIRA and Confluence.

Client: The Travellers Companies, Inc (https://www.travelers.com/)

- Technologies include UFT, VB Script, Chai, Mocha, HP ALM, Soap UI.
- Automated tests using an in-house framework (Travtest), and designed E2E Automation Scripts.
- Performed functional and regression testing, created test plans and conditions.
- Participated in organizational activities like goal tracking, seminars, and coding games.

OrchestrateHR Solutions Private Limited.

Madurai, India

Application Developer

Aug 2017 – May 2018

- Technologies include ASP.Net, VB Script, SQL, Telerik Grid, Telerik Report Designer.
- Designed various forms and web pages.

CERTIFICATIONS / TRAINING

- Automation Anywhere Certified Advanced RPA professional.
- Attended few trainings in UIPath RPA.
- Udemy courses on Python, Chai, Mocha, MongoDB, Elasticsearch, Cucumber.
- Java Backend Development track in Jetbrains.

EDUCATION

B Tech (IT) — K.L.N. College of IT, Sivagangai. (CGPA 8.3)